Prasad S Murthy

Contact

Ph: +91 91 08 45 69 19

Information

Email: prasad.sudhakar[AT]outlook.com, http://psudhaka.github.io

Profile

I have ~ 12 years of experience in conducting research and designing solutions for problems in machine intelligence using tools from signal/image processing and deep learning/AI. In the last 8 years, the focus has been on problems involving medical images. My research interests include inverse problems, model driven deep learning, data-efficient learning, etc. Apart from value generation through IP and publications, I am engaged in translating AI research prototypes into real-world deployable applications.

Since August 2022, I am also a visiting faculty at the Department of Computational and Data Sciences (CDS), IISc, Bangalore.

Research EXPERIENCE

- Staff Scientist, Advanced Technology Group, GE HealthCare, Bangalore, India. March 2019 - till date
- 2. Research Scientist, AI and Image Analytics, GE Global Research, Bangalore, India. October 2014 - February 2019
- 3. Postdoctoral research assistant, Univérsité catholique de Louvain, Belgium September, 2011 - May, 2014
- 4. Visiting researcher Ecole Polytechnique Federale de Lausanne, Switzerland January 2011

MENTORSHIP

- 1. PhD supervisor Hariharan Ravishankar, CDS, IISc, Bangalore; since August 2020
- 2. VTU nominee Board of Studies for the Department of AI/ML, RV College of Engineering, Bangalore; since June 2022
- 3. Course instructor Centre for Continuing Education, IISc, Bangalore; since August 2020

EDUCATION

- Ph.D., INRIA Rennes Bretagne Atlantique, Rennes, France, 2011
- M.Sc. (Engg.), Indian Institute of Science, Bangalore, India, 2007
- B.E., Computer Science and Engineering, Bangalore University, India, 2000

- Past employment 1. Applied Research Lab, Satyam Computers, Bangalore, India, 2006-2007
 - 2. Inspiration Technologies Pvt. Ltd., Bangalore, India, 2003
 - 3. Ittiam Systems, Bangalore, India, 2001-2002
 - 4. Robert Bosch India Limited, Bangalore, India, 2000-2001

PUBLICATIONS

Deep Learning and AI

- 1. H. Ravishankar, N. Paluru, P. Sudhakar and P. Yalavarthy, Inference Time Adaptation for Retinal Disease Diagnosis using Optical Coherence Tomography Images, submitted to Biomedical Optics Express, 2023.
- 2. H. Ravishankar, R. Patil, D. Anand, V. Singhal, U. Agrawal, R. Venkataramani and P. Sudhakar, Stochastic Weight Perturbations along the Hessian: A Plug and Play Method to Compute Uncertainty, in UNSURE-MICCAI 2022, Singapore.

- 3. D. Anand, P. Annangi and P. Sudhakar, Benchmarking Self-Supervised Representation Learning from a Million Cardiac Ultrasound Images, in EMBC 2022, Glasgow, Scotland.
- 4. P. Annangi, P. Sudhakar and M. Washburn, From 2D Ultrasound to Patient-Specific 3D Surface Models for Interventional Guidance, in EMBC 2022, Glasgow, Scotland.
- 5. H. Ravishankar, P. Sudhakar and P. Yalavarthy, Unsupervised Inference-Time Patient Specific Adaptation Method for Generalized Deep Semantic Segmentation, submitted to IEEE Journal of Biomedical and Health Informatics.
- D. Anand, R. Patil, U. Agrawal, R. Venkataramani and P. Sudhakar Towards Generalization of Medical Imaging AI-models: Sharpness-aware minimizers and beyond, ISBI 2022.
- P. Sudhakar, R. Langoju, A. Narayanan, V. Chaugule, V. Amilneni, P. Cheerankal and B. Das. Self-supervised Deep Learning for CT Deconvolution, SPIE Medical Imaging 2021
- 8. U. Agrawal, A. Hegde, R. Langoju, P. Sudhakar, B. D. Patil, R. K. Sundar and B. Das, Enhancing z-resolution in Axial CT Volumes with Deep Residual Learning, SPIE Medical Imaging 2021.
- H Ravishankar, R Venkataramani, S Anamandra, P Sudhakar and P Annangi, Feature Transformers: Privacy Preserving Lifelong Learners for Medical Imaging, in MICCAI 2019, Shenzen, China.
- H. Ravishankar, R. Venkataramani, S. Thiruvenkadam, P. Sudhakar and V. Vaidya, Learning and incorporating shape models for semantic segmentation, in MICCAI 2017, Québec city, Canada.
- R. Venkataramani, S. Thiruvenkadam, P. Sudhakar, H. Ravishankar and V. Vaidya, Filter sharing: Efficient learning of parameters for volumetric convolutions, in NIPS workshop on Machine Learning for Healthcare, 2016, Barcelona, Spain.
- H. Ravishankar, P. Sudhakar, R. Venkataramani, S. Thiruvenkadam, P. Annangi and N. Babu and V. Vaidya, Understanding the Mechanisms of Deep Transfer Learning for Medical Images, DLMIA workshop, MICCAI 2016, Athens, Greece.

Sparsity and Compressed Sensing

- P. Sudhakar, L. Jacques, X. Dubois, P. Antoine and L. Joannes, Compressive imaging and characterization of sparse light deflection maps, SIAM Journal on Imaging Sciences, 8(3), 1824-1856, 2015.
- 14. P. Sudhakar, L. Jacques, A. Gonzalez, X. Dubois, P. Antoine and L. Joannes, Compressive acquisition of sparse deflectometric maps, in SampTA 2013, Bremen, Germany.
- 15. A. Benichoux, P. Sudhakar, F. Bimbot and R. Gribonval, Well-posedness of the frequency permutation problem in sparse filter estimation with ℓ^p minimization, Applied and Computational Harmonic Analysis, 35(3), pp. 359-540, November 2013.
- P. Sudhakar, L. Jacques, X. Dubois, P. Antoine and L. Joannes, Compressive schlieren deflectometry, in Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing, IEEE International Conference on (ICASSP 2013), Vancouver, Canada.
- 17. A. Benichoux, P. Sudhakar and R. Gribonval, Well-posedness of the frequency permutation problem in sparse filter estimation with ℓ^p minimization, in SPARS'11, Edinburgh, Scotland, June 27-30, 2011.

Signal and Image Processing

- 18. A. Adiga, S. Mulleti, P. Sudhakar and C. S. Seelamantula, Two-Dimensional FRI Signal Reconstruction Using Blind Deconvolution, SampTA 2015, Lausanne, Switzerland.
- 19. P. Sudhakar and P. K. Ghosh, Recognition benefit of articulatory features from acoustic-to-articulatory inversion using sparse smoothing, INTERSPEECH 2014, Singapore.
- P. Sudhakar, L. Jacques and P. K. Ghosh, A sparse smoothing approach for Gaussian mixture model based acoustic-to-articulatory inversion, ICASSP 2014, Florence, Italy.
- S. Prasad and K. R. Ramakrishnan, On resampling detection and its application to detect image tampering, in IEEE International Conference on Multimedia and Expo (ICME 2006), July 2006.

Blind Source Separation

- A. Benichoux, P. Sudhakar, F. Bimbot and R. Gribonval, Some uniqueness results in sparse convolutive source separation, in International Conference on Latent Variable Analysis and Source Separation, Mar 2012, Tel Aviv, Israel.
- S. Arberet, P. Sudhakar and R. Gribonval, Estimating multiple filters from stereo mixtures: a double sparsity approach, in SPARS'11, Edinburgh, Scotland, June 27-30, 2011.
- S. Arberet, P. Sudhakar and R. Gribonval, Wideband Doubly-Sparse Approach for MITO Sparse Filter Estimation, in Acoustics, Speech and Signal Processing, IEEE International Conference on (ICASSP 2011), May 2011.
- P. Sudhakar, S. Arberet and R. Gribonval, Double Sparsity: Towards Blind Estimation of Multiple Channels, in Latent Variable Analysis and Signal Separation, 9th International Conference on (LVA/ICA2010), September 2010.
- P. Sudhakar and R. Gribonval, Sparse filter models for solving permutation indeterminacy in convolutive blind source separation, in SPARS'09 Signal Processing with Adaptive Sparse Structured Representations, April 2009.
- P. Sudhakar and R. Gribonval, A sparsity-based method to solve the permutation indeterminacy in frequency domain convolutive blind source separation, in ICA 2009, 8th International Conference on Independent Component Analysis and Signal Separation, March 2009.

Neuroscience

- 28. P. Sudhakar, R. Madhavan, R. Mullick, E. T. Tan and S. Joel, Method to functionally parcellate the brain consistently across subjects, Human Brain Mapping 2016, Geneva, Switzerland.
- P. Sudhakar, R. Madhavan, R. Mullick, E. T. Tan and S. Joel, Reproducibility of group spectral clustering of the sensorimotor cortex, Human Brain Mapping 2016, Geneva, Switzerland.

PATENTS

17 filed; 3 granted.

OTHER INFORMATION

Reviewer

• Nature Scientific Reports, MICCAI, IEEE TCSVT, IEEE ICASSP, ICIP, SampTA, SPCOM